(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
DAIDAIDAI 重大発表
SAKURAMIKO 3D LIVE
DAIDAIDAI Major Announcement
緊急配信
さくらみこ 重大発表
Emergency Stream
Sakura Miko Major Announcement
おー、始まったねー。
Oh, it's started, hasn't it?
始まりましたねー。
It has started.
どうも、白上フブキです！
Hello, I'm Shirakami Fubuki!
星街すいせいです！
I'm Hoshimachi Suisei!
イエーイ！とりあえずなんかね、みこさんに呼ばれて
我々スタジオに来ましたけど...
Yay! Anyway, we've come to the studio
because Miko-san called us, but...
うん。なんかみこちいない...
Yeah. Mikochi isn't here...
いないし、何をするか分かんないし...
She's not here, and we don't know what we're doing...
全く何も聞かずにやってきた。
We came here without hearing anything at all.
この白い空間、真っ白すぎる！
This white space, it's way too white!
しかも結構広いよ、だって。
And it's quite spacious, actually.
広いよ！みこさーん！
It is! Miko-saaann!
あ、もう同化しちゃってる。
Oh, she's already blending in.
あれ？フブさんどこー？
Wait, where's Fub-san?
いるよ！ここに！バカ野郎！
I'm here! Right here! You dummy!
あ、すいません。あ、いいですか？
そろそろ...お二人とも...
Ah, excuse me. Ah, is it okay?
It's about time... you two...
あ、なんか声がする。天の声？
Oh, I hear a voice. A voice from the heavens?
うん、あのー、二人ともね、座っていただいてね。
Yeah, um, both of you, please have a seat.
はいはいはい。
Okay, okay.
ありがたいね。あ、じゃあちょっとあのー、VTR？
I appreciate it. Ah, then, a... VTR?
あ、なるほど。なんかあるんだ。
Ah, I see. There's something.
VTRを一緒にね。
Watch the VTR together, right.
Vがあるんだ。じゃあ一緒に「どうぞ」するか。
There's a V. Then shall we do the "Please watch" together?
わかりました。せーの！
Got it. One, two...!
どうぞ！
Please watch!
2018年。
2018.
2018年
世間が藤井聡太プロの
史上最年少七段昇進に沸く中...
While the world was abuzz with
Pro Sota Fujii's promotion to 7th dan as the youngest ever...
史上最年少 7段昇進
Youngest Ever Promotion to 7th Dan
美少女ゲームとアニメは人生の教科書
Bishojo games and anime are life's textbooks
彼女は産声を上げた。
She let out her first cry.
はーい！ということで、にゃっはろー！
Hi! So, Nyahallo!
名は、さくらみこ。
Her name is Sakura Miko.
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
電脳桜神社で巫女として活動するアイドルVTuberだ。
She's an idol VTuber active as a shrine maiden at the Cyber Sakura Shrine.
人はさくらみこをこう呼ぶ。
People call Sakura Miko this:
エリートと。
"Elite."
愛らしいルックス。
Adorable looks.
等身大のキャラクター。
A relatable character.
そして、コンプレックスだったという独特の声を武器へと変え、
And, turning her unique voice tone, which she used to have a complex about, into a weapon,
台北の皆さんにゃっはろー！
Nya-hello everyone in Taipei!
その熱狂は海を超えた。
The enthusiasm crossed the seas.
スターへの階段を一気に駆け上がるさくらみこ。
Sakura Miko quickly climbs the stairs to stardom.
しかし、デビュー当初は...
However, at the beginning of her debut...
みこのファンの人って全然いなかった。
There were no Miko fans at all.
アイドルになりたい。
I want to be an idol.
ちゃんと頑張りたい。
I want to work hard.
「悔しい」って実感したんですよ。
I truly felt "frustrated."
悔しさを糧に、誰よりも忍び耐え続けた極貧生活。
Fuelled by frustration, she endured a life of extreme poverty more than anyone else.
そんな痛みも持ち前の明るさで乗り越えてきた。
She overcame such pain with her natural brightness.
そして今夜、新たなステージへと導く重大発表が。
And tonight, a major announcement that will lead to a new stage.
みこが走馬灯の時に絶対に出てくる、
I think it'll be something very meaningful
すごい思い入れのあるものになるんじゃないかなって、人生の中で思いますよ。
that'll definitely appear when my life flashes before my eyes.
さくらみこの人生に刻まれる、
A new page to be engraved in Sakura Miko's life
新たな1ページが今夜明かされる。
will be revealed tonight.
プロジェクトM エリートの流儀
Project M: Elite's Way
風の中のすばる 砂の中の銀河
Subaru in the wind, a galaxy in the sand
みんなどこへ行った
Where has everyone gone,
見送られることもなく
without even being seen off
草原のペガサス 街角のヴィーナス
Pegasus on the plains, Venus on the street corner
みんなどこへ行った
Where has everyone gone,
見守られることもなく
without even being watched over
地上にある星を 誰も覚えていない
No one remembers the stars on the ground;
人は空ばかり見てる
people are only looking at the sky
にゃっはろー！ あえんびえん
Nya-hello! Aen-bien
でやまれ！ あんたお？
Dyamare! Anda-o?
あっちゅ！ あっちゅ！ あっちゅ！
Atchyu! Atchyu! Atchyu!
エリートみこ激動の6年。今夜、重大発表。
Elite Miko's turbulent 6 years. Tonight, the major announcement.
さあ、改めて始まりました。プロジェクトM エリートの流儀。
Now, we've begun once again. Project M: Elite's Way.
今回の進行をする白上フブキと、
I'm your host, Shirakami Fubuki, and...
星街すいせいです。
...Hoshimachi Suisei.
いやー、とんでもなくドラマチックに始まりましたけども。
Wow, that started off incredibly dramatically.
これ、あの番組ですよね？完全にね。
This is THAT show, right? Totally.
そうですね。これはちょっと私もですね、お世話になっております、あの曲の...
Exactly. This is, well, from that song I'm also familiar with...
あの曲！そうですね、パロディでしょうね。
THAT song! Yeah, it's definitely a parody.
なんかね、歩いてました、我々。
And for some reason, we were walking in it.
ね。何でしょうね、あれ。
Right. What was that all about?
記憶がないです。歩いた記憶が。
I have no memory of it. No memory of walking like that.
本当そう。歩いた記憶がないし、こんな風に歩いた覚えはないし、
Me neither. I don't remember walking like that at all.
なんかASMRっぽい感じしましたけども。
It kind of felt like ASMR, too.
面白かったですね。
It was entertaining.
まあ、このあと何か重大発表があるらしいですね、これ。
Well, apparently there's a major announcement coming up later.
あ、そうなんですね。なんかもう、後ろにちょっと出てる。
Oh, is that so? It's actually already partially visible behind us.
後ろにね。なんかもう出てる。何なんですか、これ。
Behind us, yeah. It's already there. What is this?
なんかちょっと、気になるものが出ておりますけれども。
Something quite intriguing is being displayed.
まあね、気になるところなんですが。
Well, it's certainly curious.
本日の主役をお呼びしましょう。
Let's call out today's protagonist.
はい、どうぞ！
Please, come on out!
いよっほー！
Iyo-ho!
皆さん、にゃっはろーです！
Nya-hello, everyone!
どうも。エリート、さくらみこです。
Hello. I'm the elite, Sakura Miko.
本日はお集まりいただき、どうもありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for joining us today.
どうもね。いやー、感動的だったなぁ。
Hello. Wow, that was really moving.
大塚明夫さんに「エリート」って言わせんの、変。
Having Akio Otsuka say "Elite" is just weird.
あ、そうだよ。
Ah, you're right.
何言わせてんの、エリートって。誰なんですか。
What are you making him say "Elite" for? Who is he?
座り方がちょっと偉そうですね。
Your way of sitting looks a bit arrogant.
本当だよ、偉そうじゃん。
True, you look so high and mighty.
今日はね、もうDAIDAIDAI重大発表だからね。
Well, today is the BIG, BIG, BIG major announcement.
もう、これぐらいの...
So, I need at least this much...
もう、すごーい持ち上げてくれたでしょうね。
They really hyped me up, didn't they?
なんかすごかったね、VTR。
The VTR was quite something.
みことんでもないなと思ってさ。
I was thinking, "Miko is incredible."
なんかちょっと気持ちよかったというか、ありがたかったよ。
It felt a bit good, and I was grateful.
あっちゅあっちゅ、あえんびえん、PONと呼ばれる日々とかね、あったね。
"Atchyu, atchyu," "Aen-bien," "Days called PON," and all that.
あれちょっと... あれ編集したの誰なの？
But wait... who edited that?
あれ誰なの？あれ編集したの誰なの？
Who was it? Who edited that?
わからないです。
We don't know.
ちょっと今頃ですけど、あそこら辺で...
It's a bit late now, but around there...
笑ってる、ほら、座って！笑ってるから！
They're laughing, look, sit down! They're laughing!
笑ってる人いますけれども、はい、はい、はい。
There are people laughing, but yes, yes, yes.
これなんかちょっと、なんであの番組のパロディにしてしまったんですか？
Wait, why did you make this
a parody of that program?
やっぱ壮大さ...
Because of the grandness...
あ、壮大さで。やはりすごいなと思って。
Oh, grandness. I thought it was amazing.
あとやっぱさ、もうこの重大発表ってものをするなら、
And if I'm going to make
this major announcement...
ああいう感じの、なんていうの、もう...
I wanted that kind of, how do I say it...
「すごいんだよ！」っていうところをさ。
"It's amazing!" kind of vibe.
すごくない？ここまでアホっぽくできるの。
Isn't it amazing? How she can look so stupid.
え、すごいよね。「すごいんだよ！」って。すごい動画だったね。
It is. "It's amazing!"
That was an amazing video.
そうそうそう。何一つ伝わらなかったけど、この発表に関して。
Yeah. But nothing was conveyed
about the actual announcement.
まあただただすごいなっていうのは、本当にあのナレーターの...
Well, the thing that was purely amazing
was the narrator's...
大塚...
Otsuka...
そう、大塚芳忠さんの声で。声で察したんだ、みこ。
Yes, Otsuka Houchu-san's voice.
I recognized the voice, Miko.
うわ、本物や！って。
Whoa, it's the real deal!
そうだよ！あれはすごかったね。
Exactly! That was incredible.
みこも本当に感動でね、もう、本当にもうなんかありがたい限りでございます。
I was really moved too.
I'm just so very grateful.
あのエリートダッシュマンって。
That "Elite Dash-man."
そな！そな！そな！
Sona! Sona! Sona!
はい。ということで、みこさんの後ろにね、よく分かんないですけど大年表があるので。
Alright. Well, behind Miko,
there's this grand timeline.
ここからはね、みこさんの歴史を振り返っていきたいなと思いますよ。
From here, let's look back at Miko's history.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はいはい。じゃあまず2018年見ていきましょうか。
Okay. First, let's look at 2018.
2018年の5月1日にX初投稿。
May 1st, 2018: First X post.
そうだよ。
That's right.
ほら、3ヶ月空いて8月1日から。
See, three months later,
starting from August 1st...
結構空いてるんだね。
That's quite a gap.
本当はデビューがね...
Actually, my debut...
ここだけの話なんだけど、デビューはやっぱさくらみこなわけさ。
Between you and me, I'm Sakura Miko, right?
春にデビューしたいじゃん。さくらが咲いてる頃に。
I wanted to debut in Spring,
when the cherry blossoms are in bloom.
あ、したかったんだ。
Oh, you wanted to?
だけど大人の事情でダメだったんだ。
But it didn't work out
due to adult circumstances.
だから8月になったの。もう散ってたよね、さくら。
So it became August. The blossoms were long gone.
え、じゃあ本当は5月にデビューしたかったの？
Wait, so you actually wanted to debut in May?
そう。5月っていうかもっと前にデビューしたかったんだけど。
Yes. Well, May, or even earlier than that.
まあ大人の事情でなかなか難しいよね。
Well, adult circumstances make it difficult.
難しい時代よ。
It was a difficult time.
まあ、この時代って特にね、今よりもっと難しかったね。
Yeah, it was especially harder back then.
私もね、この2018年の3月ですから、デビューが。
I also debuted in March of 2018.
あ、そうだよね。
Oh, that's right.
3月。私の方が先輩なんで。
March. So I'm your senior.
あ、先輩なんで。
Ah, you're the senior.
あの、敬っていただいてもよろしいですか？
Could you please show me some respect?
いや、でも今日は違うから。
No, today is different!
今日はみこさん主役だからね。
Because Miko is the star today.
仕方ないな。
Can't be helped, then.
そして、その年の25日、クリスマスにホロライブ加入。
And on Christmas of that year,
she joined Hololive.
そうなんです。
That's right.
半年ぐらい空いて、ついにという感じでね。
After about a six-month gap,
it finally happened.
まあ満を持してね。
Well, the time was ripe.
満を持してっていうか、まあ、元々ね、色々あったんだよね。
Well, not so much ripe as... there were various things.
また大人の事情だ。
Adult circumstances again.
ちょっと端折っていかないと、まだまだありますからね。まだまだありますね。
We better speed up, there's a lot more.
There's plenty left.
まずオリ曲も来まして、一周年来まして、セカンド...
Original songs, 1st anniversary, second...
あ、さくらかぜありましたね。
Oh, "Sakurakaze" was there too.
ありましたね。そして7月19日にMiComet結成ですね。
It was. And on July 19th,
MiComet was formed.
あの、4周年おめでとうございました。
By the way, happy 4th anniversary.
あ、やりました。ありがとうございます。
Oh, we did it. Thank you.
初期MiComet激甘、あの二人と絡みたかったんだけど、なんかすごいチュッチュしてたんだね、昔は。
Early MiComet was so lovey-dovey.
I wanted to join in, but they were all over each other.
え、だってさ...
Well, because...
おえっ！おえっ！
*Retching noises*
おまえ、やめろよ！
Hey, cut it out!
やめてフブさん！そこを掘り下げないでよ！
Stop it, Fubuki-san! Don't dig that up!
違う、まだ記憶が上書きされてないの。
No, it's just that the memory
hasn't been overwritten yet.
もう何の記憶もないから今。消し去れよ、もう。何も覚えてない。
I have no memory of that now. Erase it already.
I don't remember a thing.
初期MiComet消し去らないでよ！
Don't erase early MiComet!
もう知らない。
I don't know her.
一旦初期はね、ちょっと置いてきたよね。
We kind of left our early days behind.
あ、置いてきた。もう4周年で全てを浄化させたから、もう終わり。
Left behind. The 4th anniversary purified
everything, so it's over.
あ、そうなの。でもこれからのMiCometは？
Oh, really? But what about MiComet from now on?
これからのMiCometは、まあ変わらずね。
Future MiComet will stay the same.
ビジネスですから。なるほどね。いこうかなと。
Since it's a business. I see.
Let's move on then.
はい。そして2021年ね。新衣装お披露目ありまして。
Alright. Then 2021. There was a new outfit reveal.
そして7月30日、100万人突破。ありましたねー。
And on July 30th, 1 million subscribers.
That happened.
おめでたい。
Congratulations.
2021年なんだね。そして2021年一大ニュース。
So it was 2021. And a big news of 2021.
100万人より一大ニュースね。
An even bigger news than the 1 million.
12月16日、運命の加湿器。
December 16th: The fateful humidifier.
運命の加湿器。いらない！なんか...
The fateful humidifier. I don't need that!
I mean...
これって3年前だったんだ。
Was that really three years ago?
そうなのよ。だのにあんなに擦られてるの、未だに。
It was. And yet it's still being rubbed in even now.
去年の話だと思ってたよ、もう。いつまでも擦るんだよ。
I thought it was from last year!
You just keep rubbing it in.
いやまさかのね、だってあれはもうだて、シャープさんが反応してしまったから。
Well, unexpectedly, it's because
SHARP responded to it.
シャープさんがね。シャープさん見てる？見てる？待ってるよ！
SHARP-san. SHARP-san, are you watching?
Are you? I'm waiting!
ということは、もしかしてこの重大発表、あのシャープさん絡みですか？
So, is this major announcement
related to SHARP by any chance?
違います。全然違います。
No. Not at all.
噂されてはいたけど。
There were rumors, though.
あ、そうなの。なんだー。そして2022年に。
Oh, really? Too bad. And in 2022.
はい。12月、なんか12月色々あるね。27日、五目並べ。
Yes. December... there's a lot in December.
The 27th: Gomoku.
そういう時期なのかな、五目並べ。
Is that the season for Gomoku?
そうやね、12月にあったんだね。
Yeah, it was in December.
そうだね、フブさんとのありましたね。あれね、屈辱的な。
That's right, the one with Fubuki-san.
That humiliating one.
え、ちなみにですけど、最近ね、やったんですよ、すいちゃんと。
By the way, I played against Suisei-chan recently.
やってましたね。
You did.
そしたらね、みこ勝ったの！
And I won!
あ、もういい、どうでもいいよ。ね、次。
Okay, fine, who cares. Next.
次ね、はい。で、2023年に。
Next, right. And in 2023.
鳴門鯛焼本舗さんコラボがありましたね。
The Naruto Taiyaki Honpo collaboration.
大好きなね、鯛焼き屋さんとついにコラボという感じでね。大喜びでね。
Finally a collab with my favorite Taiyaki shop.
I was so happy.
我が家にも運んできました。はい、もうみんなに運びました。
She even brought some to my house.
Yes, I brought them to everyone.
みこ食べたいわけ。
I want to eat them.
おい、じゃあ食べようかな、いものやつ食べたいなっつって
Hey, so I thought I'd eat, I wanted the sweet potato one,
「分かったー」っつって、さくらあんばかり持ってきた。いもなかった
and you said "Got it!" but only brought cherry blossom.
There was no sweet potato.
でもさくら美味しかったからな。また食べたいなあれな
But the cherry blossom one was delicious.
I want to eat it again.
東京都観光大使就任、もありましたね。びっくりしましたね
And I was appointed as Tokyo Tourism Ambassador.
That was surprising.
ね。ハイタッチしてた
Yeah. You were doing high-fives.
8月2日に、ファーストEPが…　あー！出ましたね！
On August 2nd, the 1st EP... Oh! It came out!
え、もうこれ去年なんだ
Wait, this was already last year?
ね、去年なんだ。びっくり、1年経ったんだ
Yeah, it was last year. Wow, a year has passed.
そうだよ、もう1年経ってんだよ。あっという間だね、月日はね
That's right, a year has already passed.
Time flies, doesn't it?
で、今年に入りまして。22日に鳴門鯛焼本舗さんとのコラボ第2弾の
And entering this year, on the 22nd, the second
collaboration with Naruto Taiyaki Honpo...
ありましたね。にゃんにゃんにゃんの日ね。ありがたいよ
That happened. On Cat Day. I'm grateful.
ありまして、そして4月9日に200万人突破で！
And then, on April 9th, reaching 2 million subscribers!
ありがたい、本当に。そして本日、7月21日に、
このなんかDAI DAI DAIがなんかね、3つ続いてからの重大発表ってね
Truly grateful. And today, July 21st, after those
three 'Major's, we have a major announcement.
こうやって見たらダダダに見えるけどね
Looking at it like this, it looks like 'Da-da-da'.
ダダダ重大発表ということでね。ははー、なんなんでしょうね
A 'Da-da-da' major announcement. Haha, what could it be?
ねー、一体何の発表が控えているのか、楽しみでありますけども
I wonder what kind of announcement is waiting,
I'm looking forward to it.
はい。どうやって発表されるんです、これ？
Yes. How will this be announced?
いや、だからドーンってくる。今、ちょっと言っていただきましたけど
Well, it'll go 'Bam!'. Just as you mentioned.
言うわけないじゃん。まだやないの、言うわけないじゃん
I'm not gonna say it. Not yet, I'm not gonna say it.
えー、なんだ。まだ、ちょっとまだVTRあるんです
Oh, come on. Still, there's still a VTR.
VTRあるんだ。これだけではありません
There's a VTR. This isn't all.
あ、Mikoさんの紹介して終わるだけかと思ってた
Ah, I thought it would just end with Miko's introduction.
全然、まだありますよ。いろいろ頑張りましたからね、ということで
Not at all, there's more. I've worked hard on various
things, you see.
はい。実はね、まあ密着ってちょっとロマンじゃない、みんな
Yes. Actually, a documentary follow-up is a bit
of a dream, isn't it?
密着？どういう密着？
Follow-up? What kind of follow-up?
こうやってギュッギュッギュッて密着？ミコベト密着？
Like, hugging tightly? A Miko-Suisei squeeze?
違う違う、あっちの方。あの、ほら、今撮ってますよーみたいな
No, no, the other kind. You know, like 'we're filming
right now'.
そうそうそうそう。密着してもらったんです。そのVがあるということで
Exactly. I had them follow me. And we have that footage.
え、気になる。Mikoさんの日常が見れるってこと？
Wait, I'm curious. Does that mean we can see Miko's
daily life?
Mikoさんの日常は、見れるってこと、今からじゃあ。密着ってことは
Miko's daily life, you can see it from now.
That's what a follow-up means.
え、あのさ。もしかして今日そんなんでもない重大発表が
くると思ってらっしゃいます？
Um, you know. Could it be you're thinking today's
major announcement isn't that big of a deal?
わかんない、だって我々。何も聞いてないですから。
とりあえず、こうやって進めてくださいって言われてるだけだもんね
We don't know. We haven't heard anything. We were
just told to proceed like this.
だってシャープさんとのコラボじゃないって言ってたし。
鳴門鯛焼本舗さんもやったしなーみたいな感じなんです
I mean, you said it's not a collaboration with Sharp.
And you already did Naruto Taiyaki Honpo, so...
Mikoさんの日常に密着してどうすんだよって
What are you going to do by following Miko's daily life?
ちょっと待てよ、いや、どうせだらしない日常見せられるだけだろ
Wait a minute, I bet it's just showing your lazy
daily life.
ああもう、見栄っ張り。絶対見栄張ってる
Oh man, such a poser. You're definitely posing.
見栄張ってない！こんな椅子に座ってる時点だよ。
いや、みんな同じ椅子座ったよって
I'm not posing! Look at me sitting in this chair.
Well, we're all sitting in the same chairs.
そう。本当に。まあまあ分かりました、じゃあ気になるな
Yes. Really. Alright, alright, well then, I'm curious.
あ、気になるかもしれない。どんなVTRなんだろう
Ah, I might be curious. What kind of VTR is it?
見栄っ張りのVTR気になる。だらしなーい毎日。
お腹出して寝てる毎日
I'm curious about the poser VTR. Your lazy daily life.
Sleeping with your belly out every day.
違うでしょ。え。フブミコメット、見て、これ3D、初めてなんだね、3人で
That's not it. Look. FubuMikoMet, see, this is the
first time in 3D for the three of us.
あ、そうなんだ、3人ではね
Ah, I see, for the three of us.
今日はMikoちゃんのすごい日なんだよね。すごい日らしいね。
もっと褒めてもっと褒めて。そしたらどうぞって言うわ
Today is Miko-chan's big day. Praise me more, praise
me more. Then I'll say 'Here you go'.
わー、見たい見たい。Mikoちゃんのすごいとこ見たい。
キミはキミの乳酸菌。イエーイ、にゃっはろーワールド
Wow, I want to see Miko-chan's greatness.
You are your own lactic acid bacteria. Yay, Nya-hello World.
え、これを見たらね、Mikoのこと見直しますよ
Wait, once you see this, you'll see Miko in a new light.
それじゃあ、用意しちゃおうかな。お願いします
Then, shall I get it ready? Please.
それじゃあ、行きますよ。VTRご覧ください。うー、VTRスタート！
Then, here we go. Please watch the VTR.
Uuu, VTR start!
エリートみこ、真の姿
Elite Miko, the True Self
密着初日
First day of follow-up
何ー！重大発表VTRー！
What! Major Announcement VTR!
重大発表ー！
Major announcement!
そらあ、密着ってそういうもんだから。重大発表する時のリハー
Well, that's what a follow-up is like. This is the
rehearsal for the major announcement.
DAI DAI DAI
Major Major Major
おはようございます
Good morning
あ、あ、おはようございます
Ah, ah, good morning.
今日からだっけ？密着。あ、どうぞどうぞ撮ってて
Was it from today? The follow-up. Ah, go ahead,
feel free to film.
今、何をされてたんですか？
What were you doing just now?
うるさいよ。今、あの重大発表の『発表〜』か
『DAI! DAI! DAI!』のほうかちょっと悩んでて
Shut up. I was just wondering whether to say the
'Announcement~' or 'Major!' part.
『重大発表』って何ですか？
What is the 'Major Announcement'?
重大発表は... まだ内緒だ
The major announcement is... still a secret.
サプライズ感
The sense of surprise...
大事にしてっから
...is something I really value.
この日は 3Dライブのリハーサル
On this day, a rehearsal for the 3D live.
歌う前のこだわりとかあるんですか？
Do you have any specific things you focus on before singing?
うまく歌えなくても
Even if I can't sing well,
愛嬌で頑張ろう
I'll do my best with charm.
今は何をしてるんですか？
What are you doing now?
体を清めてるみたいな
I'm purifying my body, sort of.
降ろしている 神を
I'm bringing down... the god.
これが一番 大事だ
This is the most important part.
神を降臨させる儀式はどれくらいかかる？
How long does the ritual to descend the god take?
3時間
Three hours.
巫女だからね さくらみこ
I'm a shrine maiden, after all. Sakura Miko.
名前 覚えてる？
Do you remember my name?
ちょっとね〜 舐めてるね〜
You're... looking down on me a bit.
新入りです
I'm a newcomer.
みこは何年にデビューしてると思う？
What year do you think Miko debuted?
2019年？
2019?
2018年ですね
It was 2018.
みこ どんな人に見える？
What kind of person do I look like to you?
PONな人？
A clumsy person?
PONな人ぉ！？
A clumsy person!?
見て！ この草 映して！
Look! Film this grass!
これ 1本1本 頑張ってるでしょ？
Each blade is doing its best, right?
でも時に 踏みつけられるでしょ？
But sometimes, they get stepped on, right?
それでも 頑張ってる みこ そういう人
Even so, they keep going. Miko is that kind of person.
う〜ん そろそろいい？
Well, can we wrap it up now?
カメラ下げてもらっていい？
Could you lower the camera?
えりーた！ えりーとまだーれ！？
Elite! Who's an elite!?
みこ！
Miko!
ありがとう みんなー！
Thank you, everyone!
さくらみこを体現する言葉
The word that embodies Sakura Miko...
エリート
...'Elite'.
こう呼ばれることに対して どう思っているのか
What does she think about being called this?
エリートと呼ばれるプレッシャーは？
What's the pressure of being called 'Elite' like?
プレッシャー？ 感じなくなってきましたね
Pressure? I've stopped feeling it.
だんだん体が慣れてきたっていうか
It's like my body has gradually gotten used to it.
エリートじゃないみこって みこって言えないかなって
I feel like a Miko who isn't elite isn't really Miko.
程遠い存在に1回なってみたいですね
I'd like to try being something far removed from it once.
ポンコツの人いるじゃないですか？
You know how there are clumsy people?
あれ どうやってるんだろう？って
I wonder how they do that.
みこさんも配信でよくPONするけど...
Miko-san, you often 'PON' in your streams too, though...
えっ？
Eh?
PONの時？
When I 'PON'?
そのPONって思ってるもの全て エリートへ繋がる道だから
Everything you think is a 'PON' is actually a path leading to being 'Elite'.
0点とるじゃないですか？
Suppose you get 0 points.
10点とったら 「スゲー」 ってなりますよね
If you then get 10, people go 'Amazing!', right?
日頃PONやってるのは エリートと呼ばれるための種蒔きみたいなもんす
Doing 'PONs' daily is like sowing seeds to be called 'Elite'.
そろそろ開花するんじゃない？ エリート
Isn't it about time to bloom? Into an elite.
さくらみこのどこがエリート？
In what way is Sakura Miko elite?
彼女をよく知る4人に 話を聞いた
We spoke to four people who know her well.
どんな配信でも あ、ここは撮れ高だ！ と思うところがすごく分かるし
In any stream, I can clearly tell, 'Ah, this is a highlight!',
それを見て私たちもニッコリできる
and seeing that makes us all smile.
そこはすごくエリートだなって思います
I think that's very elite of her.
エリートなのかはちょっとわからないんですけど...
I'm not sure if she's elite, but...
本人的には 「エリートじゃない」 って言って欲しいのか
Personally, I wonder if she wants me to say she's NOT elite,
「エリートだよ」 って言って欲しいのか どっちなんだろうって考えてて
or that she IS elite. I've been thinking about which it is.
同業者が この子はエリートだよ と言っちゃうと
If a colleague says 'This girl is elite',
さくらみこというキャラクターが崩れていくというか
her 'Sakura Miko' character might collapse.
「PON」 って言ってあげたほうがいいのか...
So maybe it's better to call it a 'PON'...
どっちでも言えるので 合わせます
I can say either, so I'll go with whatever's needed.
エリート 社会や集団の中で優秀とされる人間や集団
Elite: People or groups considered excellent within a society or group,
あるいは指導的・支配的な役割を受けもつ層 ということだそうなので
or the class that takes on leading and dominant roles.
まあ どちらでしょうね
Well, I wonder which it is.
みこさんは優秀だとは思いますけど
I think Miko-san is excellent, but...
判断は難しいので そちらで審議お願いします
...it's hard to judge, so please deliberate on that yourselves.
さくらみこ重大発表について聞いてみた
Asking about Sakura Miko's major announcement
そして、今回の重大発表については...
And as for this major announcement...
もっともっとみんなに知ってもらえて、
I'm sure it will be an event where
さらにこれからの活動が飛躍するための、
more and more people will get to know her,
そういうイベントに絶対になると思います。
and her future activities will take off even further.
意味？
The meaning?
一言で言えないかも...
I might not be able to say it in one word...
素敵な出来物、出来事。
A wonderful occurrence, event.
このイベントはみこちのエリートの見せ所だと思います。
I think this event is a chance for Mikochi
to show off her "Elite" side.
とはいえばあまり気負わず、ポンコツを見せつけたっていい。
That said, she shouldn't feel too pressured;
it's okay to show off her "ponkotsu" side.
実情、顧客のニーズはエリートではなくポンコツのさくらみこなので。
In reality, the customers' needs are not
for an elite, but for the ponkotsu Sakura Miko.
一つステップアップしていくような、
It's something that will let her take a step up
ファンの方をより楽しませるようなことができる。
and entertain the fans even more.
隔世の感があるというか。
It feels like a different era, or something.
今夜の重大発表を前に、
Before tonight's major announcement,
どうしても挑戦したいことがあるという。
she says there's something she absolutely wants to challenge.
その場所が、ま、日本一なんですよ。
That place is, well, number one in Japan.
ま、そこに挑戦して羽ばたいちゃおうかなって。
Well, I thought I'd challenge that and spread my wings.
I can fly.
彼女はそう言い残し、ある場所へと向かった。
Leaving those words behind, she headed for a certain place.
高さ日本一、岐阜バンジー。
Japan's highest, Gifu Bungee.
あの魚住さんおよそ100人分の高さから飛び降り、
She is said to jump from a height equivalent
to about 100 Uozumi-sans,
重大発表に向けて覚悟を決めるのだという。
to firm up her resolve for the major announcement.
また新たなスタートになると思います。
I think it will be a new start.
一つの転換期。
A turning point.
どうちよう... 怖えな〜。
What should I do... It's scary~.
トップとフォワード、前に思いっきりジャンプね。
Top and forward, jump with all your might.
思いっきりジャンプ？
Jump with all my might?
そう。
Yes.
うわ〜 一面 緑だなあ。
Wow~ It's green as far as the eye can see.
オーマイゴッド、本当に？
Oh my god, really?
本当。
Really.
いや〜〜〜 ヤバイ。
No~~~ This is bad.
タンマタンマ、タンマね。
Hold on, hold on. Wait a sec.
オーマイガッ、オーノーノーノー、ノー。
Oh my god, oh no no no, no.
ちょっちょっちょっ、ちょっとタンマ。
Wait wait wait, just a second.
足が動かない。
My legs won't move.
誰か助けて。
Someone help me.
一旦 下へ座る。
I'll sit down for a bit.
戻る戻る。
Going back, going back.
恐怖のあまり、足が前に出ない。
She's so terrified her legs won't move forward.
このまま飛ばずに終わるのか？
Will it end like this, without her jumping?
さくらみこの決断は？
What is Sakura Miko's decision?
死なない？
I won't die?
死なない。大丈夫。
You won't die. You're fine.
大丈夫だよね？
I'm okay, right?
大丈夫。
Okay.
オッケー。
彼女には大切にしている一つの流儀があった。
She had a single "style" that she cherished.
諦めない、心
Never-giving-up heart
うわぁ〜〜 怖い。
Waaaa~~ Scary.
真っ直ぐ前向いてて。下を見ないで。
Keep looking straight ahead. Don't look down.
オッケー、行きましょう。5, 4, 3, 2, 1, バンジー！
Okay, let's go. 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, Bungee!
絶対成功させるぞ〜！
I'll definitely make this a success~!
ギャアアアアア！こわああああ〜〜！
Gaaaaaaaah! It's scaryyyyyy~!
えっ！怖っ！
Eh! Scary!
うわあああ〜〜！怖ぇ〜〜！
Uwaaaaaaa~~! Scary~~!
はあ... 生きた... 生き残ったよ。
Haa... I'm alive... I survived.
生きててよかった、本当に。
I'm glad I'm alive, really.
まだまだやりたいことって、死ぬほどあるんだなって。
I realized there's still a ton of
things I want to do.
こんなところで死んじゃダメなんだなって。
I can't die in a place like this.
引き上げてもらう間、必死に、
While I was being pulled back up, I was desperately
生きるんだ、生きるんだって、すごい耐えてたの。
thinking, "Live, live." I was enduring it so hard.
何が引っかかった？
What got caught?
あの紐みたいなやつ。
That string-like thing.
スタッフが追い込んだ？
Did the staff corner you?
何やってくれとんねん！
What the heck are you doing?!
みこちゃんが死んじゃったかもしれないのよ？
Mikochi could have died, you know?
かなりの損失だよ！
That would be a huge loss!
自分で「やろう」って言ったけどね。
Even though I'm the one who said "Let's do it".
枠にハマらないエリート。
An "Elite" who doesn't fit in a box.
信じた道を進む姿に、心を動かされているのかもしれない。
Perhaps we are moved by the way
she follows the path she believes in.
エリートとは、
Elite is...
みこにとってエリートは
For Miko, being an elite means
諦めずに努力し続けて
continuing to work hard without giving up
咲き誇れる人
and being someone who can bloom proudly.
諦めそうになることたくさんありますからね
There are many times when I feel like giving up.
忘れられないぐらいツライことって
Things that are so painful you can't forget them...
後々（のちのち）の自分の糧になるというか
...become nourishment for yourself later on.
出始めて全然ファンの人も少ない頃に
Back when I first started and had very few fans,
バーチャルお渡し会っていうのがあって
there was a virtual handout event.
みこのファンの人って全然いなかったの
There were almost no Miko fans.
その時に唯一一人来てくれた、みこ目当てで
At that time, there was only one person who came just for Miko.
あれ救われたよね
That really saved me.
アイドルになりたいちゃんと頑張りたいって
I wanted to be an idol and work hard properly,
まだまだ頑張りたいって
I wanted to keep doing my best.
「悔しい」って実感した
I truly felt that frustration.
過去の自分がいたから今の自分がいられるって死ぬほど思うし
I strongly feel that I am who I am today because of my past self.
ツライこともいっぱいあったけど
There were many painful things,
それが今の「みこの味」になってる
but they have become 'Miko's flavor' today.
見てるかみんな！
Are you watching, everyone!
すごいよ！
It's amazing!
でっかくなったな！
I've grown so big!
はーい！
Yeah!
涙が出るねみんな、あれ？
Everyone's tearing up, huh? Wait...
涙は...出てないけど...
Tears... aren't coming out, but...
ああ、涙が...
Oh, the tears...
泣いちゃう...
I'm gonna cry...
泣いちゃってる、みんな！すごいよ！
Everyone's crying! It's amazing!
誇らしいよ！
I'm so proud!
誇らしい...
Proud...
ね、すごかった？
Right? Was it great?
でもバンジーは頑張りましたね！
But I really worked hard on that bungee jump!
やばい怖すぎたんだけど、あれ
That was way too scary.
VTRで白上も震え上がってたからね
Fubuki was trembling during the VTR too.
そうだよ、高いとこダメなんだよ
Exactly, I'm bad with heights.
無理だよ！
It's impossible!
なんででしょう、フブさん？
I wonder why, Fubu-san?
なんでホロメン飛びたがるんだよ、そんなさ
Why do Hololive members want to jump so much?
おかしいよ！
It's crazy!
え、なんかちなみにコツがあるんでしょ？
By the way, there's a trick to it, right?
コツ？そう、飛ぶコツ
A trick? Yeah, the trick to jumping.
頭から...
From the head...
あ、そうそう、こうやってね
Ah, yeah, like this...
こうやって立つでしょ
You stand like this.
で、このまま足でピョンって言ったら
And then you just hop with your feet...
もう一気にグワンってなるわけだから
and then you go 'whoosh' all at once.
怖いのね
It's scary.
こう行くの？
You go like this?
そう、だから何度も教えてもらったんだけど
Yeah, so I was taught many times.
こうやってやって、「山見て山見て」って言われて
I did this, and they told me 'look at the mountain, look at the mountain.'
山見て... こう行くの！こうやって！
Look at the mountain... and go like this! Like this!
ああ、こうやって行くんだ
Oh, so that's how you go.
こうやって行くの！
You go like this!
なるほどね
I see.
それはなおさら怖いですわ
That makes it even scarier.
やばいですよ
That's crazy.
やばいんだよ、本当にすごいことなんだから！
It's crazy, it's really an amazing thing!
いや、素晴らしかったですけど
It was wonderful, though.
いや、すごいね
Yeah, amazing.
で、重大発表ってあのバンジーしたってこと？
So, the huge announcement was that bungee jump?
なわけねーだろ！
As if!
あ、違うんだ
Oh, it's not.
それは確かに、走馬灯で流れる映像でしたけど
That was certainly a video that would play in a life review.
走馬灯にも流れるけど、結局何なんですか？
It would, but what is it after all?
ね、なんか見てもわかんなかった
Yeah, I couldn't tell even after watching.
全然わかんなかった
Not at all.
見たい？
You wanna see?
うん
Yeah.
まだ内緒
It's still a secret.
なんだよ！
What the heck!
じゃ、この後何があるんだよ
So, what's next?
えっと、この後はですね、ミニライブがありまして
Well, after this, there's a mini-live...
おお、楽しみ！
Oh, looking forward to it!
その後に、発表すると！
And after that, the announcement!
おお、緊張してきた！
Oh, I'm getting nervous!
ミニライブ何歌うんですか？
What are you singing for the mini-live?
え、何歌うっていうのは、みこの曲だとか
Well, what I'll sing... Miko's songs and...
まだ振り付け、踊ったことない、みんなもまだ踊ったことない曲とか
songs with choreography I've never danced, and you guys haven't seen yet...
それがすんげー大変なんだよ！
That's really tough!
こんなやつだ
It's something like this.
あ、そうそう、これこれ！
Ah, yes, this one!
これが来る？
This is coming?
これが来るの、はい
This is coming, yes.
あとは？
What else?
色々
Various things.
色々かよ！台本のこれ読んだほうがいいって
Just 'various things'!? You should read this part of the script!
あ、そうだった！
Ah, that's right!
ちなみに、新曲も初披露します！
By the way, I'll also perform a new song for the first time!
おお、新曲！
Oh, a new song!
ということで、私たちの出番はじゃあこれで終わりだ
So, our turn is over for now.
そうだよ、信じられる？
Yeah, can you believe it?
信じられるね
We can.
はい、しらみこめっとさんです
Yes, we are Shiramicomet.
いえーい！
Yay!
ねえ、もうこれで終わっちゃうの名残惜しいですけれども
It's a shame it's ending like this...
本当だよ、これだと私たちのからも重大発表教えてよ
Really. Tell us the huge announcement too.
教えてよ、せっかもう帰るからさ
Tell us, since we're leaving soon.
しょうがないな、二人でラーメン行っておいで
Can't be helped. Go get some ramen, you two.
ごにょごにょ...
(Whispering...)
え！？マジで！？
Eh!? Seriously!?
本当にマジ？
Really, seriously?
すいちゃんには...
And for Sui-chan...
ごにょごにょ...
(Whispering...)
うわー！やばいよこれ！
Whoa! This is crazy!
ああ...
Oh...
すいちゃん！大丈夫！？
Sui-chan! Are you okay!?
まさか... あの、みこさんがだよ
No way... that Miko-san would...
もっと...
More...
ああああ...
Aaaaaah...
ライブ行ってこい！
Go do your live!
ということで、じゃあみこね、ライブ準備してきます！
So, Miko will go prepare for the live!
みんな楽しみにしててねー！
Everyone, look forward to it!
いってらっしゃーい！
See you!
いってきまーす！
I'm off!
そうだったね
That was it, huh.
まあ、是非頑張っていただきたいですね
Well, we really want her to do her best.
それでは行きますか、みこさんのライブです！
Shall we? It's Miko-san's live!
どうぞ！
Please!
にゃっはろーわーるど！ さあ行こう！ エリートは面舵いっぱーい！ 参上！
Nyhello World! Let's go! Elite, hard a-starboard! Arriving on the scene!
配信だ、今日も集まれ！
It's a stream, gather 'round today too!
幕開けは愛だ、叫べ！ 育ち盛りのあほ毛！
It starts with love, shout it out! A growing ahoge!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！
Nyhello World!!!
わがままでガタいも繰り返し 手の込んだ進呈、一歩前！
Repeating selfishness and stubbornness, an elaborate presentation, one step forward!
不変な名残惜しさは去るぜ あらやだ顔前な、飛んで未来！
Unchanging lingering regrets are gone! Oh my, facing forward, fly to the future!
さあ、声を上げて(にゃっはろー！) 山あり谷あり、下見を済ませ、そんな根性
Come on, raise your voice (Nyhello!)! Through ups and downs, finishing the preview, that kind of grit!
さあ、声を上げて(にゃっはろー！) 今に見とけ、エリートのしまっちゃう、べ、べ、べ、べ、べいべー！
Come on, raise your voice (Nyhello!)! Watch me now, an Elite's gonna tuck it away, be-be-be-be-baby!
凡骨もやがて羽ばたくバタフライ
Even a mediocre person will eventually spread their wings like a butterfly.
毎日努力を満たしたら 逆境は無限余裕じゃ
If you fulfill your efforts every day, you'll have infinite ease in adversity.
にゃっはろーわーるど！ さあ行こう！ 全身全霊、声を上げろ！
Nyhello World! Let's go! With heart and soul, raise your voice!
右に左、緑にサンキュー、なんてな！
Left and right, thank you for the green, just kidding!
にゃっはろーわーるど！ さあ行こう！ エリートは面舵いっぱーい！ 参上！
Nyhello World! Let's go! Elite, hard a-starboard! Arriving on the scene!
配信だ、今日も集まれ！
It's a stream, gather 'round today too!
赤信号も燃やすわ 真顔で使いに自重
Burning red lights too, self-restraint while running errands with a straight face.
思い出決まってろ、ケートラ 水がなくなっても、だ、だ、だ、だ、だ、だいじょーぶ！
Memories are set, K-truck! Even if there's no water, it-it-it-it-it's okay!
光ってほら、虹色じゃんね 一人ずつ名前を呼ぶよ
Look, it's glowing in rainbow colors! I'll call out each name one by one.
アイ・アン・ビ・エ・ス、つつがないね この千秋楽を羽に波
I-A-M-B-E-S, all good! Spreading this closing performance on the wings of the waves.
怨念全開、パンデミック 闇を潜ったあとも、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽい捨て
Full grudge, pandemic! Even after diving through the darkness, th-th-th-th-throw it away!
逃げない、遂げない、痛くないね アラウンド世の中も諦めんぞ
I won't run, won't stop, it doesn't hurt! I won't give up on the world around me either.
筆が走り出すね 馬耳に東風風吹かせて、飛んで未来！
My brush starts to race! Let the east wind blow on deaf ears, fly to the future!
さあ、声を上げて(にゃっはろー！) これがエリート、恥を撒き散らせ
Come on, raise your voice (Nyhello!)! This is an Elite, scatter your shame around.
さあ、声を上げて(にゃっはろー！) 世界一の人生を独行で、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、まんまー！
Come on, raise your voice (Nyhello!)! Going through the best life alone, ju-ju-ju-ju-just like that!
現人もやがて羽ばたくバタフライ
Even mortals will eventually spread their wings like a butterfly.
さあ、どこまでも行こう みんな、命燃やそうぜ！
Come on, let's go everywhere! Everyone, let's burn our lives!
哀しみも、この場所、淋しい思いさせないよ
Even sadness, in this place, I won't let you feel lonely.
みこ、みこ、ぴー、みんなで作る 特等席なんてな！
Miko, Miko, Pi, the special seats we all make together, just kidding!
にゃっはろーわーるど！ さあ行こう！ 世界中で大声を上げろ！
Nyhello World! Let's go! Raise your voice all over the world!
推しも推さざる、いいよ、なんてな！
Supporting or not, it's fine, just kidding!
にゃっはろーわーるど！ さあ行こう！ エリートは面舵いっぱーい！ 参上！
Nyhello World! Let's go! Elite, hard a-starboard! Arriving on the scene!
配信だ、今日も集まれ！
It's a stream, gather 'round today too!
赤見後輩様が笑っていた 夢を届け
Akami-kouhai-sama was laughing, deliver the dream!
もっと遊べ、画面越しでハイタッチ 目を覚まして、な、な、な、な、な、ならーず！
Play more, high-five through the screen! Wake up, be-be-be-be-becoming!
光ってほら、虹色じゃんね
Look, it's glowing in rainbow colors!
一緒に、ほら、光って、つつがない名前を呼ぶよ
Together, look, shine, I'll call your names without fail.
いくよっ？
Going!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！ きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！
Kyun-kyun Miko-kyun! Kyun-kyun Miko-kyun!
君にみこきゅん！
Miko-kyun for you!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅん♡
Kyun-kyun Miko-kyun-kyun♡
ねぇねぇ、あのね、ガチ、みんな友達、夢見るカタチ、でっかい声で、マジ
Hey, hey, listen, seriously, everyone's a friend, the shape of dreaming, with a loud voice, really
それはすなわち、成長中って話、いろんなワタシ、超見て欲しい
That means I'm growing, I want you to see so many versions of me
エリート挨拶、みんなにゃっはろー！
Elite greeting, everyone, Nyhello!
エリートスマイル、ふふっふー、ぴゃー！
Elite smile, fufuffu, pyaa!
エリートダンス、みーみーみこみこ！
Elite dance, Mi-Mi-Miko-Miko!
エリートイングリッシュ、I'll be back!
Elite English, I'll be back!
ま、ね、時位はね、落ち込んじゃうこともあるよ
Well, you know, sometimes you just get depressed
そんな時は、はなまるあげるにぇ！
In those times, I'll give you a gold star!
おまえら、よく聞けーーーっ！！！
You guys, listen up!!!
今日も一日、よくできました〜！
You did a great job today too~!
こにゃちて、こにゃちて、こにゃちたまじから、推しちゃおかな、みこきゅん
Konyachite, konyachite, since konyachita serious, maybe I'll support you, Miko-kyun
ぽにゃっけ、ぽにゃっけ、ぽよったら最後、うにゃうにゃしよう？ いっしょに、せーの！
Ponyakke, ponyakke, if you're feeling dazed, let's go mumble-mumble? Together, one-two!
ドキドキみこみこきゅんきゅん！
Doki-doki Miko-miko Kyun-kyun!
とことこみこみこきゅんきゅん！
Toko-toko Miko-miko Kyun-kyun!
キラキラみこみこきゅんきゅん！
Kira-kira Miko-miko Kyun-kyun!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん、君にきゅんをあげるよ
Kyun-kyun Miko-kyun, I'll give you a "kyun"
ねぇねぇ あのね これね こっち
Hey hey, you know, this, over here
ほっぺはもちもち
My cheeks are soft and squishy
みんなのみこち
Everyone's Mikochi
ズッキュンときてマジ！
I'm totally falling in love!
それはすなわち
That's to say
摩訶不思議な話
A mysterious story
それはイケメンだし
Because it's quite handsome
超見てほしい！
I really want you to see!
エリート拍手！パチパチパチパチ
Elite applause! *clap clap clap clap*
エリートジャンプ！ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん
Elite jump! *hop hop hop hop*
エリートおねんね！むにゃむにゃグーグー
Elite sleep! *mumble mumble Zzz Zzz*
エリートわがまま！ヤダヤダわー！
Elite selfishness! No, no, waaa!
だっていつだってありのままを伝えたいの
Because I always want to show you my true self
おまえさぁ、みこをなめてんじゃねー！！
You... don't underestimate Miko!!
ふざけんじゃねーぞ！！
Don't mess with me!!
...って言えって言われましたーっ！！
...is what I was told to say!!
ほにゃってほにゃってほにゃ止まったら
When I go 'honya' and stop for a moment
ギュンしちゃうからみこきゅーん！
You'll be hooked on Mikokyun!
ぽよってぽにっておよったら
When I go 'poyo' and 'poni' then wobble
天才！うにゃうにゃしてもいいんじゃない？
Genius! Isn't it okay to mumble a bit?
せーの！
One, two!
ピカピカみのみのめきゅん！
Sparkling Mino-Mino-Me-Kyun!
フワフワみのみのめきゅん！
Fluffy Mino-Mino-Me-Kyun!
ミナミナみのみのめきゅん！
Everyone Mino-Mino-Me-Kyun!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん
Kyun kyun Mikokyun
この今が宝物
This moment right now is a treasure
いつも愛をありがとう
Thank you for the love, always
ここからはね、みこのターン！
From here on out, it's Miko's turn!
ついてきてね！
Follow me, okay!
ハイ！ハイ！みんな、コメントで合いの手してね！
Hi! Hi! Everyone, join the call and response in the chat!
いつまでも いつまでも ずっとずっと笑顔でいようね
Forever and ever, let's always stay smiling together
みこ頑張るよ！頑張れるよ！
Miko will do her best! I know I can!
もっともっときゅんになってね
Please fall for me even more
ラストにもう一回張り切って～！
Let's give it our all one last time~!
みこちゃんは～？エリートです！！
Miko-chan is...? Elite!!
ほにゃってほにゃってほにゃ止まったら
When I go 'honya' and stop for a moment
ギュンしちゃうからみこきゅーん！
You'll be hooked on Mikokyun!
ぽよってぽにっておよったら
When I go 'poyo' and 'poni' then wobble
天才！うにゃうにゃしよう一緒に！
Genius! Let's mumble together!
せーの！
One, two!
ドキドキみのみのめきゅん！
Heart-pounding Mino-Mino-Me-Kyun!
ぴょこぴょこみのみのめきゅん！
Hoppy-hoppy Mino-Mino-Me-Kyun!
キラキラみのみのめきゅん！
Twinkling Mino-Mino-Me-Kyun!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん
Kyun kyun Mikokyun
君にきゅんもあげるよ
I'll give you a 'kyun' too
みんなー まだまだいくよ
Everyone, there's still more to come!
アワーツリー
Our Tree
ねえ 思い出したんだ
Hey, I remembered
そっと 涙した日を
The days I shed tears softly
さあ 数えてみようか
Come, let's count them up
これまで起こした奇跡を
The miracles we've created until now
満たした 止まらない足で
Fulfilling them with unstoppable steps
二人 紡いでゆく夢も
The dreams we two spin together
三つ 繋がる絆は
Three, the bonds that connect us
君と広げてきたんだよ
We've expanded them with you
何度でも 咲くように 続いていくこのストーリー
So it blooms again and again, this story continues
まだ見たことのない 景色を探しに行こう
Let's go find scenery we've never seen before
花びら一枚ずつが 小さくてもほら
Even if each petal is small, you see
支え合えたら 桜になれるよ
If we support each other, we can become a cherry blossom tree
僕らが繋いだ 大きな木はまだ
The big tree that we connected will still
これからも 春風に乗って 伸びていくのさ
Keep growing from now on, riding on the spring breeze
満たした 涙こぼれたら
If tears fall from being fulfilled
二つ 両手を叩いて
Two, clap your hands together
三つ 数えて始めよう
Three, let's count and begin
君といれば大丈夫
As long as I'm with you, I'll be fine
弱音吐いて泣いたり 諦めかけたルートも
Whining and crying, even the routes I almost gave up on
振り返ればほら いつだって強くなれたんだ
Looking back, see, I could always become stronger
花びら一枚ずつが 挫けそうでもほら
Even if each petal is about to break, look
支え合えたら 大樹になれるよ
If we support each other, we can become a great tree
手と手を合わせた 形は花びら
The shape of our hands joined together is a petal
この気持ち 言葉すら超えて 届けるのさ
These feelings, going even beyond words, I'll deliver them
さえない私は
For my dull self
好きになってくれたこと
That you came to like me
これからも 後悔なんてさせないように 見ててね
From now on too, please watch me so you'll never regret it
意地を張ってた頃よりも 強く大きくなったでしょ
I've grown stronger and bigger than when I was being stubborn, right?
もっと 君を...
Even more... you...
あなたの側になりたいな
I want to be by your side.
空に願う 涙を預けて
I wish on the sky, entrusting my tears.
そろそろ僕も一歩踏み出すよ
It's about time I take a step forward too.
僕らが育てた 大きな木はほら
Look, the big tree we've grown together.
こんなにも日だまりのような場所になったよ
Has become such a warm, sunny place.
ねぇ 見せてくれたよね こんなに素敵な未来
Hey, you showed me such a wonderful future.
さぁ まだまだ続くよ これからもずっとありがとう
Come on, it's still going. Thank you for everything from now on too.
それでは、重大告知どうぞ！
Now then, here's the major announcement!
自分らしさってなんだろう？
What does it mean to be myself?
上手く言えなかったわたしへ
To the me who couldn't say it well.
ひとりで探してきた
I've been searching for it alone.
仲間と見つけてきた
I found it with my friends.
キミが見つけてくれた
You found it for me.
さくらみこになるまでの物語
The story of becoming Sakura Miko.
さくらみこ 1st Album 発売決定!!
Sakura Miko 1st Album Release Confirmed!!
ありったけの花束を
A bouquet of all I have.
Sakura Miko 1st Album flower rhapsody
思うままに歌ったこの歌声が あなたの芽吹きになるように。
May this singing voice, sung as I felt, become your budding.
エリート巫女 アイドルストーリー
Elite Miko Idol Story
さくらみこ 1st ソロライブ 開催決定!!
Sakura Miko 1st Solo Live Event Confirmed!!
Sakura Miko 1st Live flower fantasista!
このライブでみんなと分かち合いたい！
I want to share this live with everyone!
みんな、ついてきて！
Everyone, follow me!
桜は咲き誇る 満開の舞台へ！
To the stage where the cherry blossoms are in full bloom!
はーい！ということで！
Hi! And with that!
なんと！ファーストアルバム発売と！
Can you believe it! A first album release and...
そして！みこの夢だったソロライブの開催が！
And! The solo live that was Miko's dream...
ついに！決定しましたー！
...has finally been confirmed!
すごーい！
It's amazing!
えー、会場はですね、有明アリーナ！土曜日だよ、みんなすごいよ！
The venue will be Ariake Arena! It's on a Saturday, everyone, it's incredible!
いや、ついにね、みんなに伝えられて、みこはもう胸がいっぱいだけど
Man, finally being able to tell you all, Miko's heart is just so full, but...
まだね、本番じゃないからね、あれなんですけど
...it's not the actual show yet, so you know...
や、でも本当に本当に、ここまでたくさん応援してくれたみんなのおかげです！
But really, truly, it's thanks to everyone who has supported me so much up to this point!
あとみこの頑張り！スタッフさんの頑張り！
And also Miko's hard work! The staff's hard work!
もういろんなね、ホロメンの支えもあって！
And with the support of various Hololive members too!
ついに、みこの一つのね、大きな夢が叶うということで、みんな嬉しいよね！
Finally, one of Miko's big dreams is coming true, so everyone's happy, right!
めっちゃ嬉しいよね！
You're super happy, right!
もうすぐ6周年。もうすぐ6周年でね、
It's almost the 6th anniversary. Almost the 6th anniversary,
もうずっとね、まあ密かに夢見た時期から、
and for a long time, since the time I secretly dreamed of it,
声を大きく、あー、声を大きくして
to the time I started saying
「やりたいやりたい」って言った時からもういろんな時期がありましたけど、
"I want to do it" louder and louder, there have been many different phases,
いろんな時期から応援してくれた35P、
from the 35P who have supported me through all those times,
そして最近あの見に来てくれた35Pとか、
to the 35P who started watching me recently,
まだ35Pじゃないよって人にも、
and even to those who aren't 35P yet,
もうめちゃくちゃ素晴らしいライブをお届けしたいなと思っておりますので、
I want to deliver a truly wonderful live performance,
皆さんぜひ、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
so everyone, please, please look forward to it.
そしてアルバムもね、もう本当に頑張ります。
And I'll work really hard on the album too.
頑張りましたから。みんなぜひね、あの買ってほしいですね。
I've already worked hard on it. I really want everyone to buy it.
ということで、じゃあ詳細はみんな説明していきます。
So, I'm going to explain the details now.
それでは、まず1つ目...
Now, first of all...
あ、そうだ。この後ね、あの最後に1曲歌うんで、皆さんぜひ最後までね、見てくださいね。
Oh, that's right. I'm going to sing one song at the end, so please watch until the very end.
じゃあまずはアルバムの宣伝からです。
Now, let's start with the album promotion.
はい、さくらみこ 1st Album「flower rhapsody」が2024年9月25日に発売決定！
Yes, Sakura Miko's 1st Album "flower rhapsody" will be released on September 25, 2024!
こちらのね、キービジュアル、野部沢先生、もちぷよ先生に、あの描き下ろしていただきました。めちゃくちゃ綺麗だよね。
This key visual was drawn by Nobesawa-sensei and Mochipuyo-sensei. It's so beautiful, isn't it?
パッケージもね、あのちょっとこだわっております。三方背ケースかな？
I've also put a lot of thought into the packaging. I think it's a three-sided case?
そう、めちゃこだわってるので、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, I've been very particular about it, so please check it out.
そして、こんなに素敵なクリエイターの皆様に参加していただきました。
And we have many wonderful creators participating.
なんとね、あの、まあ3ヶ月連続リリースしてる曲は入ってるんですが、それ以外はね、全部新曲だよ！すごい！
Amazingly, while it includes the songs released over the last three months, all the other songs are brand new! Incredible!
いやあ、もうやったね。頑張りましたね。はい。
Wow, we did it. We really worked hard. Yes.
ということで、こんな素敵なクリエイターの皆様に参加していただきました。通常盤、数量限定盤の2種類がなんとあります。
So, we had these wonderful creators join us. There are two versions: the regular edition and the limited edition.
どちらも本日この後21時より各サイトで予約開始です。
Reservations for both will start today at 9:00 PM on various sites.
まずは通常盤の紹介です。こちら、ドドン！
First, an introduction to the regular edition. Here it is!
はい、通常盤。通常盤の特典にはなんと全5種類のランダムクリアカードが1枚付いてきます。
Yes, the regular edition. The regular edition bonus is one of five types of random clear cards.
このクリアカードにはなんと、数量限定でみこの直筆サインが入ってるかも？
And for a limited number, these clear cards might even have Miko's handwritten signature!
ということでね、みんな、ぜひゲットしてみてくださいね。
So everyone, please try to get one.
さらに、各店舗でアルバムを買ってくれた方は店舗別特典が付きます。全15種類だからね。
Furthermore, those who buy the album at various stores will receive store-specific bonuses. There are 15 types in total.
お店ごとにいろんな特典があるのでみんなチェックしてね。
Each store has different bonuses, so please check them out.
そしてそして、数量限定盤の紹介です！
And now, for the limited edition!
にゃー、すごい！めちゃくちゃエモいイラストですね。
Meow, amazing! It's such an emotional illustration.
はい、こちら特典にはですね、スペシャルブックレット、アクリルスタンド、ホロライブ・オフィシャル・カードゲームのカード、
Yes, the bonuses include a special booklet, an acrylic stand, and a Hololive Official Card Game card,
そしてみこからのお手紙が入っております。これまでのね、みこを支えてくれた35Pのみんなへ感謝を込めて書きました。
and also a letter from Miko. I wrote it with gratitude to all the 35P who have supported me up until now.
そしてこの限定盤はね、パッケージもすごい豪華になってて、もうめちゃくちゃ可愛いのでぜひゲットしてほしいんです。
And this limited edition has very luxurious packaging and is super cute, so I really want you to get it.
限定盤はホロライブプロダクション・オフィシャルショップで先着販売となります。まあ、結構あるとは思うんですけど、
The limited edition will be sold on a first-come, first-served basis at the Hololive Production Official Shop. I think there's a fair amount,
ぜひね、お急ぎくださいませ。
but please hurry.
そして、封入特典のホロライブ・オフィシャル・カードゲームはなんとみこの初のカード化になります。
And the included Hololive Official Card Game card is actually Miko's first card.
カードの詳細はホロライブ・オフィシャル・カードゲームの公式Xアカウントをフォローしてチェックしてくださいね。
For card details, please follow and check the official Hololive Official Card Game X account.
続いては、お待たせしました。ソロライブの情報です！
Next, thank you for waiting. Information about the solo live!
まずはライブのキービジュアルを公開です！ドン！
First, revealing the live key visual! Boom!
いやあ、可愛い！おるだん先生に描き下ろしていただきましたよ。もうめちゃくちゃ神々しいよね。
Wow, so cute! Ordan-sensei drew this for me. It looks so divine.
公演ハッシュタグは「#咲き誇るみこち」で、みんなドンドンポストしていって盛り上げていってくださいね。
The performance hashtag is "#SakihokoruMikochi", so please keep posting and get the hype going.
続いてみんな気になるのは会場とチケット情報。今回のソロライブはなんと、有明アリーナで開催します！
Next, what everyone's curious about is the venue and ticket information. This solo live will be held at Ariake Arena!
そしてチケットはS席、A席、B席の3種類がございます。
And there are three types of tickets: S-seat, A-seat, and B-seat.
現地チケットの一次先行がこの後21時から開始となりますので、ぜひチェックしてください。
The first round of advance tickets will start today at 9:00 PM, so please check it out.
また今回はZ-aNで海外の35P向けにも現地チケットを販売します。
Also, this time, local tickets will be sold through Z-aN for overseas 35P.
また配信チケットはSPWNとZ-aNで販売します。
Streaming tickets will also be sold on SPWN and Z-aN.
こちらもあと21時から販売開始なので、会場に来れない人は配信でみこの雄姿を見に来てくださいね。
Sales for these also start at 9:00 PM, so those who can't come to the venue, please come watch Miko's valiant performance via streaming.
各座席のエリアマップはこちら。
Here is the area map for each seat.
S席は1階アリーナの前方、A席は1階の後方と2階、3階の前方、そしてB席は3階と4階に分かれております。
S-seats are in the front of the 1st-floor arena, A-seats are in the back of the 1st floor and the front of the 2nd and 3rd floors, and B-seats are divided between the 3rd and 4th floors.
続いてお楽しみのグッズ情報になります。
Next is the much-anticipated goods information.
グッズもこの後21時より販売開始です。まずは「応援セット」のご紹介です。
Goods will also go on sale at 9:00 PM. First, let me introduce the "Support Set".
35Pライト、Tシャツ、たすき風タオル、そしてセット特典のリストバンドが入っているセットになります。
This set includes the 35P Light, T-shirt, sash-style towel, and a wristband as a set bonus.
応援セット
Support Set
11,300円ですね。
It's 11,300 yen.
えー、まあこちらはですね、やっぱみこPライトはもうみんなね、絶対ゲットしなきゃいけないよねっていうのと、
Well, as for this, everyone absolutely has to get the MikoP Light, right? And...
タオルもですね、こだわり、こだわりを詰め込んだので、みんなぜひこれをね、装着して着てくださいね。
I've packed the towel with my personal touches, so everyone, please wear it and come see me!
それぞれのグッズは単品でも販売します。
Each of these items will also be sold individually.
先行発送グッズ
Pre-order Shipping Items
今回、みこPはっぴも、先行発送対象となります。やったー！
This time, the MikoP Happi is also eligible for pre-order shipping. Yay!
はっぴ、作りたい作りたいって言ってましたからね、ついに作っちゃいましたよ。
I've been saying I wanted to make a Happi, so I finally made it!
みこPのみんなは当然、フル装備で応援してくれるよね？
MikoPs, of course you'll support me in full gear, right?
はっぴは応援セットに含まれないので注意してください。
Please note that the Happi is not included in the support set.
受注生産グッズ 1
Made-to-order Items 1
さらに受注販売グッズも紹介します。
Next, I'll introduce the made-to-order items.
モチーフチャームと、えー、とっても可愛いたい焼きの形をしたポーチ付きブランケットです。
The motif charm and, well, a very cute blanket with a Taiyaki-shaped pouch.
このモチーフチャームはみこの新ビジュアルに、あの、太ももにね、巻いてるベルトをイメージして作ってるので、みんなもバッグやね、ポーチにつけてみてくださいね。
This motif charm is inspired by the belt I wear on my thigh in my new visual, so please try putting it on your bag or pouch!
受注生産グッズ 2
Made-to-order Items 2
続いて、クリアファイル & 缶バッジセットです。はい、アクリルペンライトスタンド、これめっちゃいいよね！
Next, the Clear File & Badge set. And the Acrylic Penlight Stand, this is so good, right!
これ、めちゃくちゃ素敵ですね。そしてタペストリーの紹介です。
This is really wonderful. And an introduction to the tapestry.
キービジュアル大きく、タペストリーにしたので、これを飾ってライブの余韻に浸ってほしいなと思っております。
I've made the key visual into a large tapestry, so I hope you'll display it and soak in the afterglow of the live.
最後に、注意事項です。
Finally, some notes.
販売期間はこのあと21時から8月13日18時までです。
The sales period is from 9 PM tonight until August 13th at 6 PM.
そして、注意いただきたいのがグッズの発送時期についてです。
And something I'd like you to be careful about is the shipping timing of the items.
先行グッズは、えー、ライブの前に届く予定なんですけど、受注販売グッズはライブの後にお届けします。
Pre-order items are scheduled to arrive before the live, but made-to-order items will be delivered after the live.
また、先行発送グッズは「さくらみこ 1st Album "Flower Rhapsody"」以外の商品と一緒に購入はできません。
Also, pre-order items cannot be purchased together with items other than the Sakura Miko 1st Album "Flower Rhapsody."
受注販売グッズを購入する場合は別会計でお買い求めください。
If you are purchasing made-to-order items, please buy them in a separate transaction.
詳しくは公式X、販売サイト、公式特設サイトをご確認ください。
Please check the official X, sales site, and official special site for details.
はぁ...ということで、告知は以上になります。みんな、大変だね、あははは。
Phew... so, that's all for the announcements. It's a lot for everyone, isn't it? Hahaha.
ちょっと21時からね、もうかなりいろんな情報がブワーッと出て、みんな大変だと思ってますけども、どうぞよろしくお願いします。
A lot of information is coming out starting from 9 PM, so I think it'll be tough for everyone, but please support me.
はぁ...ということでね、いや、ちょっと駆け足でやりましたけれども、皆さんどうでしたか？
Phew... so, I went through it a bit quickly, but how was it for everyone?
もう本当にみこはね、もうなんだろう、もうすごいたくさん準備もね、頑張ってきましたし、言いたくて言いたくてしょうがなかった。
Miko has really, well, worked so hard on so many preparations, and I've been dying to tell you all.
けれどね、まあ、みんなにね、黙ってないと黙ってないと、と思って、まあ、ここまで来ましたけど。
But I thought I had to keep it a secret from everyone, and well, I've made it this far.
なんか、ちょっとちょいちょいね、もうソロライブだろ、みたいにみんなやる気満々でね、いたりとかして嬉しいなって思って。
I saw everyone being so excited, saying like "It's gonna be a solo live!", and that made me happy.
もうみこPはね、もうみこのことがね、とても大好きだと思いますからね、もう今泣いてると思うわ。
I think the MikoPs really love Miko a lot, so I'm sure they're crying right now.
みこもね、あの、初めてライブできますよって言われたときはね、もう大泣きしましたね。「うわー、やっとだ、嬉しいな」って。
When I was first told I could have a live, I also cried my eyes out. "Wow, finally, I'm so happy," I thought.
みこ、まあ、アイドルとしてはね、まだまだだなって、いっぱいね、いろんなホロメンがいる中でね、みこってまだまだだよな、できないだろうなって、思っていましたけど。
I thought that as an idol, I still have a long way to go, among so many Hololive members, that I'm still not there yet and wouldn't be able to do it.
ついにね、もう本当にみんなのおかげもあって大きく育って、ついに一花咲かせれるなという感じになっております。
But finally, thanks to everyone, I've grown big, and it feels like I can finally make a flower bloom.
本当に応援してくれてる人、ありがとう。もうね、やばい、泣きそうだよ、ちょっとどうしよう、あはは。
To everyone who supports me, thank you. Oh man, I'm about to cry, what should I do? Hahaha.
はい、ということでね、まだまだありますから。最後に、1stアルバムから新曲もなんと、お披露目します！
Yes, and there's still more. Finally, I'll even be performing a new song from my 1st album!
じんさんに、作詞・作曲・編曲を担当していただきました。
Jin-san handled the lyrics, composition, and arrangement.
そして、MVもこのあと公開します。すっごい素敵になってるのでぜひ見てください。
And the MV will also be released after this. It's turned out so wonderful, so please watch it.
本日24時に楽曲もリリースするので、みんな、アルバムリリースまでたくさん聴いてね！
The song will also be released at midnight tonight, so everyone, please listen to it a lot until the album release!
それでは、聴いてください。『DAI DAI DAI ファンタジスタ』！
Now, please listen. "DAI DAI DAI Fantasista"!
にゃっほー！ ご調子はどうだい？
Nyaho! How are you doing?
弾む勝手くれ ピンクカラーへ
Bounce as you please, to the pink color.
弾けちゃってベイビー、ア・オー！
Burst out, baby, a-oh!
さあ 待ったなしだ 始めちゃえ
Now, no waiting, let's start.
今日も気合入れてやるぜ 挑戦状
I'll be fired up today too, a challenge.
躊躇は厳禁 足踏みしてないで
Hesitation is forbidden, don't just mark time.
一緒に せーので もっと前に行こうね
Let's go further forward together on "one, two, three."
さあ なんだかんだ言っちゃって 飛び込んで
Now, saying this and that, jump in,
登せちゃって じっとしてられないぜ
let's get dizzy, I can't stay still.
冒険だ
It's an adventure!
どんがらがった
Clatter and bang!
まだ止まらない
It still won't stop.
道程はこんなだ
The journey is like this.
なんなんだ
What is this?
ちょっとだった
It was just a little bit.
あは
Aha!
めちゃめちゃしゃって
Being all messy and confused,
気持ち持っちゃって
Getting all caught up in feelings,
あれ一体全体どうした？
What on earth happened there?
絶体絶命満たしには
For us in a desperate situation,
涙は似合わないんで
Tears don't suit us at all.
DAI DAI DAI 冒険に飛び出そうぜ
DAI DAI DAI Let's jump into an adventure!
いーじゃんね
It's fine, right?
DAI DAI DAI 心配も重ねて成長して
DAI DAI DAI Let's grow by piling up worries too.
ハッピーなエピソードを君と笑い話にしよう
Let's turn happy episodes into stories to laugh about with you.
うぇーい
Yay!
DAI DAI DAI 問題もぶっ飛ばせ
DAI DAI DAI Blow away the problems too.
いつか
Someday,
DAI DAI DAI 大炎上の素敵な結末へ
DAI DAI DAI To a wonderful conclusion of a grand finale.
ピース三叉路抜けて進め前代未聞のユートピアへ
Go through the peaceful junction to an unprecedented Utopia.
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
お腹も空いちゃってる
I'm getting hungry too.
またポッケとも掘ってる
Staring blankly again.
べんきょうべんきょう はいはいはい
Studying, studying, yes yes yes!
知ってます！
I know that!
まだちょっと違ってる
It's still a bit different.
ぶっちゃけ優勝、指揮者の皆に感謝してます
Honestly, it's a victory, I'm grateful to all the conductors.
ナイスコメント、まじ感謝
Nice comments, seriously thanks.
ぜんぜんおっけー
Totally okay.
うじうじしちゃって
Getting all hesitant and mopey,
心にロックしちゃって
Locking up my heart,
それだんだんだんどうして？
Why is that happening bit by bit?
絶体絶命満たしには
For us in a desperate situation,
笑顔が足りてないんで
We're lacking smiles.
DAI DAI DAI ぶきっちょも隠さない
DAI DAI DAI I won't hide my clumsiness.
いーじゃんね
It's fine, right?
DAI DAI DAI 満足のその上の感動を
DAI DAI DAI Emotions even beyond satisfaction,
もっと欲しがっちゃってここに贅沢に行こう
Let's want them more and go luxuriously here.
うぇーい
Yay!
前前前進したってへこんじゃったって
Even if I step forward or get depressed,
まだまだ
Still more!
邁進前進全開エマージェンシーの前段で
Pushing forward at full speed in an emergency.
ニャッホー！ハッピーソング響かせて進めピースだー
Nyahoo! Let the happy song resonate and advance, it's peace!
ムーヴオン、乗り遅れないでよ、みんなー
Move on, don't fall behind, everyone!
目を大きく開いてフレッシュ
Open your eyes wide and stay fresh!
歌声届け、高らかに
Let the singing voice reach, loudly!
べーべーべーなんつってね、あは
Bah-bah-bah, just kidding, aha!
なんだかちょっと色褪せない
Somehow it doesn't fade at all.
一人ぼっちで見てた光景は
The scenery I used to watch all alone,
今はきっと、あなたと冒険してる
Is now surely an adventure with you.
DAI DAI DAI...
DAI DAI DAI 大好きじゃ収まらない
DAI DAI DAI 'I love you' isn't enough to contain it.
だから
That's why,
最前最高レベルに達しの全開で
Reaching the highest level, at full power.
ニャッホー！ぶっ叩いちゃってずっと大冒険者
Nyahoo! Knock it out and be a great adventurer forever.
DAI DAI DAI 問題もぶっ飛ばせ
DAI DAI DAI Blow away the problems too.
いつか
Someday,
DAI DAI DAI 永遠の素敵な結末へ
DAI DAI DAI To an eternal wonderful conclusion.
ピース三叉路抜けて進め前代未聞のユートピアへ
Go through the peaceful junction to an unprecedented Utopia.
かき回してくれピースだー
Stir it up, it's peace!
F**king Super...
みんな！ライブ、全力で楽しもうなー！
Everyone! Let's enjoy the live show with all our might!
センキュー！
Thank you!